Contact

alejandrolmos942@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/alejandro-olmos-948333218 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Full-Stack Development Software Development Agile Methodologies

Alejandro Olmos

Senior Software Engineer (Python, Java, JavaScript) Joshua, Texas, United States

Summary

As a software engineer with over 10 years of experience, I designed, developed, tested, and maintained software systems and I used various programming languages such as Python, Java, JavaScript, and software development methodologies to create efficient and effective software solutions. Below you can see my skills in detail:

- Python, Django, Flask, FastAPI
- React, Angular, Node.js
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript
- Bootstrap, MUI, Tailwind CSS
- PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB
- RESTful API
- GraphQL
- Elasticsearch
- RabbitMQ
- AWS, Heroku, Firebase
- Git, Jira, Trello, Asana

I also worked on various types of software, including computer programs, mobile applications, and web-based systems, and I often collaborated with other engineers, product managers, and users to ensure that their software meets the needs of the stakeholders.

I'm known for patient communication, asking detailed questions, developing understandable, maintainable code, and generally having a good time and being fun to work with, even when things get difficult. In my spare time, I like to play music, go to concerts, watch NBA basketball, read novels, and cook.

Feel free to contact me any time if you have any projects. I would be happy to help you reach your business goals and make you successful.

Experience

InnovA Technologies
Software Engineering Team Lead
January 2022 - January 2023 (1 year 1 month)

- Worked on multiple software projects simultaneously and participated in the whole software development process from design to implementation and delivery.
- Developed new software functionalities, ensuring that clients' vision and requirements were met.
- Collaborated with peers on the improvement of software performance and performed error analysis; installed and maintained multiple server software.
- Recognized by executives for completing projects in a timely manner and within budget.

Wilks Brothers, LLC Software Engineer August 2019 - January 2022 (2 years 6 months)

- Built single-page web applications using JavaScript libraries/frameworks such as React and Angular.
- Created scalable back-ends serving RESTful APIs with Python/Django and Node.js.
- Developed big data pipelines.
- Wrote a Chrome extension for troubleshooting Google Analytics deployments.
- Integrated and conducted end-to-end and performance stress testing of the built tools.

DealerSocket

Associate Software Engineer April 2015 - August 2019 (4 years 5 months)

- Developed inventory tracking software with barcode scanning and printing capabilities in Python.
- Developed platform and database independent RAD tools in Java.

Education

Texas Wesleyan University
Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2012 - 2015)